<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Datafibers on DataFibers</title>
    <link>https://datafibers.org/tags/datafibers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Datafibers on DataFibers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 13:50:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://datafibers.org/tags/datafibers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Winter Release</title>
      <link>https://datafibers.org/blog/2017/12/22/2017-12-22-df-winter-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datafibers.org/blog/2017/12/22/2017-12-22-df-winter-release/</guid>
      <description>Summary Before christmas, DataFibers has completed the winter release, which has more than 40+ changes requests applied. In this release, DataFibers is featured with first demo combined both data landing and transforming in real time with new web interface. In addition, the preview version of batch processing (by spark) is ready.
Details Below is the list of key changes in this release.
 New Web admin UI released using ReactJs based AOR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Summer Release</title>
      <link>https://datafibers.org/blog/2017/08/31/2017-08-31-df-summer-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datafibers.org/blog/2017/08/31/2017-08-31-df-summer-release/</guid>
      <description>Summary A little bit data, but DataFibers has completed the summer release of 2017 about right time. In this release, we have applied 30+ changes requests. In this release, DataFibers is featured with a preview of new web interface. In addition, couple of connectors are added/updated to preparing the demo later.
Details Below is the list of key changes in this release.
 Support Flink Table API and SQL API support Flink upgrade to v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Winter Release</title>
      <link>https://datafibers.org/blog/2016/12/29/2016-12-29-df-winter-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datafibers.org/blog/2016/12/29/2016-12-29-df-winter-release/</guid>
      <description>Summary Before new year, DataFibers has completed the winter release of 2016, which has more than 20+ changes requests applied. In this release, DataFibers is featured with new api document and landing pages. In addition, the preview version of stream processing (by flink) is ready.
Details Below is the list of key changes in this release.
 Integrated REST API Document to the DF Application
 Added landing welcome page</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>